<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-04-03T07:10:10-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Charlie Chapman</title><subtitle>The personal blog of Charlie Chapman.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise 3.0: White noise, freed</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise 3.0: White noise, freed" /><published>2023-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3">&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;Dark Noise 3.0&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; released on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change in Dark Noise 3.0 is the introduction of a new free tier. This free tier includes access to 8 free sounds, as well as full support for infinitely looping sounds, Shortcuts, Siri integration, the Timer, and all the deep Apple integrations you’ve come to expect from Dark Noise. This makes the app more accessible than it’s ever been before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who want more features and sounds, there is &lt;strong&gt;Dark Noise Pro&lt;/strong&gt;. This optional subscription or lifetime in-app purchase unlocks over 50 sounds, the ability to create custom mixes, alternate app icons, and alternate premium themes. With Dark Noise Pro, you can customize your white noise experience to your liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/04/02/dark-noise-pro-compare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Tier Comparisons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on this update for quite a while, and a significant portion of that time was spent ensuring existing customers are taken care of. Customers who purchased Dark Noise before this update are called &lt;strong&gt;Dark Originals&lt;/strong&gt;. At launch, they will have all Dark Noise Pro features unlocked automatically. There &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be features introduced in the future that require a Dark Noise Pro subscription, but for now Dark Originals will receive all of the same features as Dark Noise Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 3.0 also begins the process of improving the experience of Dark Noise with headphones or nicer speakers. This update includes &lt;strong&gt;4 high quality stereo remasters&lt;/strong&gt; of existing sounds: Rain, Thunderstorm, Beach, and Airplane Interior. Future updates will include more remasters as well as a new focus on increasing the variety of sounds in Dark Noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, this update includes a plethora of small enhancements and bug fixes including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newly updated App Icon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewritten theme picker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Aurora premium theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Aurora alternate app icon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mac window size restores from previous session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 3.0 is available &lt;strong&gt;now&lt;/strong&gt; on the App Store to &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;download for free&lt;/a&gt;! I can’t wait to hear what you all think. If you’re press you can find an extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/press&quot;&gt;press-kit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/posts/dark-noise-3&quot;&gt;more details&lt;/a&gt; on the release on &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;darknoise.app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today Dark Noise 3.0 is finally released on the App Store.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-icon-v2-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-icon-v2-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise Analytics: March 2023</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/3/1/2023-dark-noise-stats" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise Analytics: March 2023" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/3/1/2023-dark-noise-stats</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/3/1/2023-dark-noise-stats">&lt;p&gt;I recently added some analytics into &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; using the new(ish) privacy-focused analytics tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://telemetrydeck.com/&quot;&gt;TelemetryDeck&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for my big update that will be adding a free tier. I want to get an understanding of how many users I might be dealing with going forward and some of my future plans lead me to want to understand what features, and sounds users are using most within the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a couple of months now so I have enough data to share some metrics with you all. I think it might be fun to see what changes when I switch to a subscription business model with a free tier. As always, this is meant to be helpful! I don’t know if these numbers are higher than average, or lower than average. This is just one data point that’s hopefully helpful to see, especially for other indie developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, let’s start with the high-level stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-overview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s only been a couple of months, but so far &lt;strong&gt;Monthly Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; have hovered right around &lt;strong&gt;11,000 to 12,000&lt;/strong&gt; unique users. For reference, App Store Connect’s “Active Last 30 Days” analytics (which are limited to only users who opt-in) shows 4,300 users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Daily Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; is surprisingly consistent at around &lt;strong&gt;2,300 to 2,500&lt;/strong&gt; unique users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-hourly-active.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Hourly Active Users&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Hourly Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; very clearly show peaks around nighttime in North America with a smaller peak in the morning confirming my assumption that a large portion of users are probably playing these sounds to go to sleep. The smaller peak in the morning is most likely because most people pause the app in the background or use the timer feature to automatically stop the sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;device-info&quot;&gt;Device Info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-device-info.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Device Info&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at device info, about &lt;strong&gt;1/5th&lt;/strong&gt; of sessions came from &lt;strong&gt;Macs vs iOS&lt;/strong&gt; which I have to admit surprised me to be that high. Good to keep in mind that the Mac does represent a significant portion of my app’s use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over &lt;strong&gt;90%&lt;/strong&gt; of sessions came from the &lt;strong&gt;latest iOS 16 or macOS 13&lt;/strong&gt;. This will be interesting to watch as I add a free tier. I think there’s a chance that a more accessible app will get a higher adoption among the less tech-enthusiast crowd which may actually increase the percentage of users I have on older OSs. Also, hello there iOS 17! 👋&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;noise-play-counts&quot;&gt;Noise Play Counts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-noise-bar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Device Info&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-noise-donut.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Noise Count Donut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow… Brown Noise is king apparently 😅.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected some popular sounds and then a long tail, but I definitely didn’t expect Brown Noise to be that dominant. It’s cool to see custom mixes are very popular though. I get a lot of positive feedback about that feature, but I always wondered how popular it was to use by most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;extras&quot;&gt;Extras&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-extras.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Extras&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of extra metrics I found interesting. There’s not a lot to analyze here other than it’s nice to have confirmation people really are using these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m definitely glad I finally added some light analytics back in the app. I think this will be really helpful in guiding decisions on what features or sounds I should focus on going forward. And while TelemetryDeck is still a little young and rough around the edges, I feel confident in that team’s focus on privacy. And even in the short few months I’ve been using it they’ve dramatically improved the reporting UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this is helpful for you all! At the very least I think it’ll be an interesting data point to look back on in a few months after my update to subscriptions and having a free tier. As always, if you have any questions or comments I’d love to hear them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@charliemchapman&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently added some analytics into Dark Noise using the new(ish) privacy-focused analytics tool TelemetryDeck in preparation for my big update that will be adding a free tier. I want to get an understanding of how many users I might be dealing with going forward and some of my future plans lead me to want to understand what features, and sounds users are using most within the app.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2022: A Break, a Breakthrough, and a Breakdown?</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2022/12/31/2022-break-breakthrough-breakdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022: A Break, a Breakthrough, and a Breakdown?" /><published>2022-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2022/12/31/2022-break-breakthrough-breakdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2022/12/31/2022-break-breakthrough-breakdown">&lt;p&gt;2022 was a bit of a weird year for me that I think kinda breaks down into 3 distinct parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A breakthrough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And… a breakdown?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-break&quot;&gt;A Break&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since switching to iOS development and launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; in 2019, I’ve been working pretty consistently hard on side project work. I wanted to establish myself in this platform and this community so I could avoid getting pulled back into web development like previously always ended up happening. Dark Noise and my podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com/&quot;&gt;Launched&lt;/a&gt; were both mechanisms to keep pushing on both the technical/product side and the community side of things. This was especially important when the pandemic showed up and made connecting with the community much more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But 2022 was different. I was finally able to travel. We had just bought a new house at the end of 2021. And &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; I was a little burnt out? I’m not quite sure the full alchemy of reasons, but from the beginning of the year to the end of the summer my side projects really took a back seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did keep producing Launched thanks to a schedule that pulled me along and a lineup of guests I was, quite frankly, extremely proud to have on. But Dark Noise development slowed to a crawl. I spun up a couple &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1504267868241862656&quot;&gt;new app ideas&lt;/a&gt; that I ran out of steam on and never released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it had an impact! Dark Noise sales were down pretty significantly the first half of the year. I had no major releases in that period and being a paid up front app meant that really hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2022/12/31/dark-noise-yearly-proceeds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise yearly sales graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;Dark Noise yearly proceeds (released in August 2019)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might all sound negative but I took advantage of this break and honestly I think I needed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got to travel! I finally met coworkers for the first time in San Diego, vacationed with my wife without kids for the first time since the pandemic, went to Europe for the very first time (with the kids!), and &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got to meet folks in the iOS community &lt;strong&gt;in person&lt;/strong&gt; at WWDC 😱.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2022/12/31/2022-flighty-passport.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Flighty Passport showing all flights I took in 2022&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://flighty.app/&quot;&gt;Flighty&lt;/a&gt; Passport showing all of my 2022 flights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in between traveling, Apple reached out asking for a demo version of the Dark Noise Mac app. And now &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1585347257737818113&quot;&gt;every Apple retail store in the world has a demo of Dark Noise pre-installed on all of their display Macs&lt;/a&gt;! 😱&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-breakthrough&quot;&gt;A Breakthrough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things happened at the end of summer that changed my side project trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dark-noise-returns&quot;&gt;Dark Noise Returns&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is simply Apple’s OS release cadence. The nice thing about Apple’s release cadence is it sort of forces me to get a release pulled together by a certain date. This year, that meant I needed Dark Noise to be ready with iOS 16 support and features like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DarkNoiseApp/status/1569328284923486211&quot;&gt;new Lock Screen widgets&lt;/a&gt; in September with a follow up release in October to support the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DarkNoiseApp/status/1584549536269148162&quot;&gt;new Dynamic Island and Live Activities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release kind of woke me up from the side project blues and got the gears going again with regards to Dark Noise development. This was partially fueled by extra time I now had because of the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; breakthrough I had at the end of summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;launched-with-help&quot;&gt;Launched With Help&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August I decided I needed some help with Launched. Editing the show was simply taking too much of my limited side project time. I wanted to hire an editor, which meant I needed money. I didn’t want to take on selling sponsorships myself given I was already stretched too thin so I started putting together a pitch deck to see if I could find a network that would let Launched join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking over the pitch deck stats I basically chickened out thinking the numbers were probably too low for anyone to consider and never even reached out to anyone. Instead I simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1561695800656379904&quot;&gt;tweeted them out&lt;/a&gt; and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, this ended up paying off! &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@refactoredd@mastodon.online&quot;&gt;Jonathan Ruiz&lt;/a&gt; had recently ended his show, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_everydayrobots&quot;&gt;Everyday Robots&lt;/a&gt;, and reached out to offer to edit the Launched. I took him up on the offer and every episode since has been edited by Jonathan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot express how big of an impact this has had. I am pretty precious with the edit of that show, but Jonathan has been outstanding. And the time it’s freed up has allowed me to pour more time into growing both the podcast (I’m gearing up to start taking on sponsorships) &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; turning Dark Noise into a potentially fully viable business into it’s own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-breakdown&quot;&gt;A Breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: ok this headline is a pretty hyperbolic for the sake of keeping the “break” theme but you have to admit it’s pretty catchy yeah?&lt;/em&gt; 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of 2022 has been… turbulent to say the least. The tech industry has suddenly gotten a little unstable. And Twitter, the platform that the hosts the community I’d invested so much in, was imploding. There are also some personal career things I can’t discuss here that put me, an extremely risk averse personality, into hardcore de-risking mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started putting together action plans. What do I do if I get laid off? How much runway do I have to find another job? Can I grow that runway if my side projects are making more money? Could my side projects &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; the other job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brewed a pretty weird concoction of excitement mixed with anxiety that’s launching me into 2023 with a pretty clearly defined set of short term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Switch Dark Noise to a subscription model.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monetize Launched with a combination of sponsorships and membership/Patreon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invest in the local (St. Louis) iOS community by starting some kind of meetup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like my goals have usually been more high-minded and &lt;em&gt;“personal growth”&lt;/em&gt; focused in years past. It feels a little crass for a major theme to essentially be &lt;em&gt;“make more money”&lt;/em&gt; but this is where I am. We’ll see where 2023 takes me, but either way I’m at least coming into it with a side-eye towards handling uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">2022 was a bit of a weird year for me that I think kinda breaks down into 3 distinct parts. A break A breakthrough And… a breakdown?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile_1024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile_1024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS 15 Support with Dark Noise 2.6</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/10/5/dark-noise-2_6-iOS-15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS 15 Support with Dark Noise 2.6" /><published>2021-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/10/5/dark-noise-2_6-iOS-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/10/5/dark-noise-2_6-iOS-15">&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 2.6 comes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;App Store today&lt;/a&gt; with full support for iOS 15!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extra-large-widgets&quot;&gt;Extra Large Widgets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/10/05/dark-noise-2_6-extra-large-widgets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Extra Large Widgets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS 15 introduced a new widget size exclusive to iPad and Dark Noise 2.6 adds support for these new big sizes. Now you can fill your iPad with 16 wide button noises, or a whopping 32 square button noises in a single widget!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course these widgets support all of the themes and customizations you’ve come to expect from Dark Noise widgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shortcuts&quot;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/10/05/dark-noise-2_6-shortcuts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Shortcuts Actions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to limitations in iOS 14, Shortcuts actions with parameters could not play audio without opening the app up in the foreground. This led to a confusing array of Shortcuts actions provided by Dark Noise. Shortcuts actions &lt;strong&gt;with parameters&lt;/strong&gt; for setting up a timer or volume (began with the word “Start”) had to open the app in the foreground to start a sound, and shortcuts with &lt;strong&gt;no parameters&lt;/strong&gt; (began with the word “Play”) were limited but could play sounds in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With iOS 15 things are dramatically simpler. New “Play [Noise]” Shortcuts actions can play noises in the background &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; have parameter options for customizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a new Shortcut action called “Find [Noise]” for advanced Shortcuts users. This action accepts a string parameter, searches Dark Noise for a matching noise, and outputs a Noise object that the new “Play [Noise]” action will accept as an input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows for more advanced automations where you want to dynamically pass in a string for which noise you would like to play.  To be honest I’m not entirely sure what the main use case for this is, but I’ve recieved enough requests for it that I thought it was worth adding. I’d love to hear from anybody who uses it to see what they’ve built!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes-and-improvements&quot;&gt;Bug Fixes and Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new timer view using iOS 15’s new half sheet popover and some minor bug fixes round out the update. This year’s iOS beta cycle has been… busy to say the least (I moved into a new house!). Things are finally settling down and I’m getting back to work on Dark Noises next major feature!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dark Noise 2.6 comes to the App Store today with full support for iOS 15!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise for Mac</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/5/25/dark-noise-mac" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise for Mac" /><published>2021-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/5/25/dark-noise-mac</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/5/25/dark-noise-mac">&lt;div class=&quot;postYoutube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wsMA6Du03J8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope;  picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise has come to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;! The sleek UI and large selection of ambient sounds you know and love are now easier than ever to use while you work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mini-player&quot;&gt;Mini Player&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/05/25/dark-noise-mac-mini-player.png&quot; alt=&quot;Big Sounds Mini Player&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking advantage of the Mac platform, a new innovative “adaptive toolbar” UI allows you to shrink your window into a Mini Player to keep Dark Noise quickly accessible while taking up very little screen space. Dark Noise for Mac also features full menu support with keyboard shortcuts to feel right at home on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-your-favorite-features&quot;&gt;All your favorite features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/05/25/dark-noise-mac-themes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Themes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of your favorite Dark Noise features are here including timers, custom mixes, widgets, and multiple themes. And with iCloud syncing, all of your custom mixes will automatically be available on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-it-now&quot;&gt;Get it now!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/05/25/dark-noise-hero-2_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Family&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise for Mac is now available on the App Store &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as a universal app including the iPhone and iPad versions. Existing Dark Noise customers will be able to download Dark Noise for Mac for free.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-mac-rounded_1024.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-mac-rounded_1024.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Overviewer Week 1</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/14/overviewer-week-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overviewer Week 1" /><published>2021-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/14/overviewer-week-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/14/overviewer-week-1">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/14/overviewer-icon-rounded-200.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overviewer app icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, when I released my new app &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2021/1/6/overviewer&quot;&gt;Overviewer&lt;/a&gt;, I honestly thought it was a pretty niche product and was just hoping it would find the few other teachers out there who it could help during this wild year of virtual learning. With that in mind, I didn’t really do much in the way of marketing like I &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2019/9/27/marketing-dark-noise&quot;&gt;did with Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt;. But it turns out, there’s more interest in turning an iPhone into a document camera than I thought! 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is tradition, I’d like to go through some quick metrics for the app launch and see if there’s anything. Let’s start with the basics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;📈 181,000 “App Units Sold” 🤯&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;📍 17,170 Sessions &lt;em&gt;(opt-in only metrics)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⭐️ 192 ratings avg 4.8 stars&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;📝 57 reviews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;💥 0 crashes 😁 &lt;em&gt;(opt-in only metrics)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, we need to address that ridiculous 181,000 “App Units Sold” number because… that’s kind of unbelievable. When something looks unbelievable there’s probably a reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first sign something weird was happening was actually immediately after launch when the app supposedly got &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1346899004878106629?s=20&quot;&gt;32,000 downloads in the first hour&lt;/a&gt;. And while “sessions” metrics are only available to users who have opted in to allow developers to see their analytics, 17,170 seems way lower than what you would expect if there were truly 181,000 users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out, school districts have access to something called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://vpp.itunes.apple.com/?l=en&quot;&gt;Volume Purchasing Program&lt;/a&gt; (VPP) that allows them to purchase apps for distribution to all Apple devices in their districts. When an app is free, admins can “purchase” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/timgostony/status/1347290649049980928?s=20&quot;&gt;as many licenses as they want&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sohojoester/status/1347280847959834625?s=20&quot;&gt;some folks on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; said they would &lt;em&gt;“generally buy at least 3x the number of devices I could possible deploy to and then deploy as needed”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So most likely these huge numbers of “purchases” are school admins grabbing way more licenses than they’ll actually use just to cover their bases. If we break down unit sales by “device” I think we can see this in the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/14/overviewer-7-day-unit-sales-devices.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;7 Day Unit Sales by Device&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you can see about 157,000 units were purchased on “Desktop” while about 24,000 were from iOS devices (and 5 on iPod touch 😆). Overviewer isn’t available on the Mac, so I think it’s safe to say those 157,000 are actually from volume licensing and only a small fraction of those ever end up downloaded to a device. But the 24,000 from iOS devices are probably mostly legitimate downloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;press&quot;&gt;Press&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These numbers are &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; higher than I was expecting! So what happened? Unlike with Dark Noise, I didn’t try to build up a big TestFlight group or reach out to the press beforehand, but I did make a simple &lt;a href=&quot;https://overviewer.app&quot;&gt;presskit&lt;/a&gt; and wrote up a &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2021/1/6/overviewer&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; with the story behind the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty quickly after releasing my blog post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://9to5mac.com/2021/01/06/iphone-document-camera-overviewer-zoom/&quot;&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imore.com/overviewer-turns-your-iphone-document-camera-zoom-calls&quot;&gt;iMore&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://knapsack.news/overviewer-for-ios-turns-your-phone-into-a-document-camera/&quot;&gt;Knapsack&lt;/a&gt; all wrote up articles about the app. This led to a lot of follow-on articles from loads of smaller blogs around the world. Then later in the day, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2021/1/6/22217200/overviewer-app-teachers-overhead-camera-iphone-zoom&quot;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt; wrote about the app! 🤯 I’m going to be honest here, seeing that pop up in my feed almost broke me. I was literally shaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have 2 theories for how I got all this press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve already built a little reputation with Dark Noise and some relationships that put me on some tech writers’ radar right out of the gate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I told a compelling, relatable story that fit a broader narrative for the world we all live in right now.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have a reputation or relationships with anybody in the press, there’s not a lot you can do for the first point. I would say making a decent press kit and cold emailing writers is probably the best you can do here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Point 2 wasn’t exactly something I did on purpose, but it was pretty clear as more articles came in that the story - &lt;em&gt;“Nerdy Dev Makes App to Help Teacher Wife with Virtual Learning”&lt;/em&gt; - was the thing a lot of folks were keying in to. It fits neatly into the narrative we’re all currently living through, where we’re trying to come up with interesting solutions to our pandemic world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think telling a compelling, relatable story when announcing your app can go a long way to help you get the word out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fadOMMpQErg&quot;&gt;tutorial video&lt;/a&gt; to try to help explain how the app works, and I think this may have inadvertently added to the personalized story behind the app since I’m the one personally showing the app off on camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sources&quot;&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/14/overviewer-7-day-sources-metrics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Overviewer Sources Metrics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the sources metrics from App Store Connect. As expected The Verge and 9to5 did a lot of the heavy lifting on the Web Referrer side, but the size of Facebook in the App Referrers initially surprised me. I searched around and found that a lot of people (usually teachers) were sharing The Verge article on Facebook. Presumably, since the Facebook app has a built in browser, any links from The Verge to the App Store would actually be counted as coming from the Facebook app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thanks-&quot;&gt;Thanks 🙏&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I’ll wrap up by saying thanks to everyone who shared the app with any teachers or educators they know who might find it useful. Seeing that this little app I made is &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1348985834897367040?s=20&quot;&gt;being used in the real world&lt;/a&gt; and helping teachers and kids learn during this wild year is extraordinarily fulfilling. I’ve also heard from some people using Overviewer for tabletop gaming with friends over Zoom which is totally awesome and not something I had considered at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet can download the app for free on the App Store &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1528900395&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. And as always, if you have any suggestions for how to improve the app, or if you find another alternate use for it outside of virtual learning, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/overviewer-icon-rounded.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/overviewer-icon-rounded.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Launched Year 1</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/13/launched-year-1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Launched Year 1" /><published>2021-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/13/launched-year-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/13/launched-year-1">&lt;p&gt;One year ago today I released my first episode of &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2020/1/13/introducing-launched&quot;&gt;Launched&lt;/a&gt;. While January 2020 feels like a different world than January 2021, I still think 1 year in is a good time to assess how the project is going compared to my initial goals. And just as I did after &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2020/1/21/launching-launched&quot;&gt;week 1&lt;/a&gt;, I’d like to run through the metrics and see if there are any interesting findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But first, some quick vanity metrics!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⬇️ 53,666 Total Downloads&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⏱ 27 hours 33 minutes of total content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;🐦 1,067 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/launchedfm&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; Followers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;⭐️ 5.0 Rating on Apple Podcasts&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;great-expectations&quot;&gt;Great Expectations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with expectations. In my &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2020/1/27/launching-launched&quot;&gt;Launching Launched&lt;/a&gt; post I explained the 3 main reasons why I started the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Any project that’s going to require a significant investment of your time deserves to have this question answered: Why? For me, there is one “altruistic” answer and two selfish ones.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I want this to exist and genuinely think other devs and creators would find it beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I think it could help me raise my profile in the community which would help with future app launches and all the nice benefits of having a strong network.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’d get to meet and talk to a bunch of interesting people whose work I really respect.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;My understanding is that the vast majority of podcasts fail to reach a substantial audience, so 1 and 2 may never happen. But 3 is a benefit I get either way, so in the end, I felt it was worth giving it a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m counting #3 as an unambiguous success ✅. Just look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com&quot;&gt;this guest list&lt;/a&gt;! I still can’t believe I got to talk to all of these people. Not only with huge inspirations for me in the iOS developer community but also internet creator heroes I’ve been looking up to for years and years like &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com/episodes/12-SethWorley/&quot;&gt;Seth Worley&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com/episodes/5-MykeHurley/&quot;&gt;Myke Hurley&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For #1, I’m giving myself a pass as well. The show exists ✅ and I’ve heard from more than one listener that they find it beneficial ✅.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#2 is a bit trickier to measure. Based only on listener metrics I’m not sure how much the show has “raised my profile” as we’ll see in the next section, but I think there’s no doubt it’s helped benefit my network within the iOS community. In a year devoid of networking events, I’ve been able to have regular long conversations with developers I admire every other week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;metrics&quot;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because Launched is an interview show my expectation for downloads was a lot of variation in each episode (since each guest brings different sized audiences along) but hopefully slow growth over time since each guest’s audience would hopefully bring a few new subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something like this:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/13/launched-expectations.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Launched Expectations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, here are the downloads for every episode in year 1. It’s separated by day 1 of release to day 90 of release since the most recent episodes haven’t been out as long and it wouldn’t be accurate to compare total downloads. So you can compare all of the “7 Days” download numbers (green) for each episode for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/13/launched-year-1-metrics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Launched Year 1 Metrics&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t at all what I was expecting 😅. After the spikyness of the first 5 episodes (which was unique in that I released an episode every day), it pretty much completely leveled off into a nearly flat line. Very few spikes and almost no valleys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to admit that, despite all my lip service about my goals not being about audience size, this was a little disappointing. Admittedly I didn’t do much in the way of marketing after the initial launch, nor do I really know what options I even have (feel free to reach out if you have any ideas 😁). I think I just incorrectly internalized that if I could bring on interesting guests and keep at it regularly that I would probably grow, despite intellectually knowing that the vast majority of podcasts don’t reach that big of an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some hope, however! Episode 20 with &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com/episodes/20-CARROTWeather-BrianMueller/&quot;&gt;Brian Mueller&lt;/a&gt; was the first episode after an extended “Back to School Break” and it saw a pretty big bump in downloads (I don’t have 90 day numbers for it yet though). And it looks like each episode after has sustained a larger average than before the break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time will tell if this is a trend or a fluke, but it does feel nice to see a little boost in the audience size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here’s the user agent and location metrics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/13/launched-listener-data.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Launched Listener Data&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t have much commentary to add here other than pointing out that Overcast having a bigger percentage than Apple Podcasts is, I think, evidence of the nerdy, iOS centric profile of my listenership 😅.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, as someone who lives in a small midwestern American city, it’s very cool to see how many countries people are listening from!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;diversity&quot;&gt;Diversity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the areas where I’ve failed my original ambitions is ensuring a diverse list of guests. Of the first 24 episodes, 14 are white men, and only 3 episodes have women guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think my failure here comes &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; scheduling and booking. My problem is I don’t know or follow enough diverse indie developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody I bring on the show is someone whose work I genuinely admire and look up to. And I really don’t think the right thing to do is to bring on token diverse people, so I need to expand my network to find the folks doing interesting work who come from different backgrounds than me. I don’t know what the best method for addressing this is though, so if you’ve read this far and you have any ideas &lt;em&gt;please&lt;/em&gt; let me know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I’m really proud of Launched. I think I’ve produced a high-quality show featuring interesting guests filled with fun and educational conversations. It’s honestly a lot of work, but for now, it’s worth all of the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 threw a curveball at everybody’s life and for me Launched helped get through it. It provided the excuse to connect with a lot of developers I was really hoping to get to meet at conferences and meetups that no longer happened this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all of you who listen, I can’t thank you enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;In the US. I don’t know how to aggregate international Apple Podcast reviews &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">One year ago today I released my first episode of Launched. While January 2020 feels like a different world than January 2021, I still think 1 year in is a good time to assess how the project is going compared to my initial goals. And just as I did after week 1, I’d like to run through the metrics and see if there are any interesting findings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/launched_artwork-1024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/launched_artwork-1024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet Overviewer</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/6/overviewer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet Overviewer" /><published>2021-01-06T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/6/overviewer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/6/overviewer">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/06/overviewer-icon-rounded-200.png&quot; alt=&quot;Overviewer app icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’m releasing &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1528900395&quot;&gt;Overviewer&lt;/a&gt;, a totally free new iOS app for teachers that can turn your iPhone into a document camera on Zoom or other video conferencing apps. It’s proven difficult to explain what the app is actually for if you don’t already know what that is, so let’s start with a quick explanation of a document camera (or visualiser for our UK friends).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/06/iOCHOW-S1-Document-Scanner-500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Document Scanner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iochow.com/product/iochow-s1-document-scanner/&quot;&gt;iOCHOW S1 Document Scanner&lt;/a&gt; - $219&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A document scanner is essentially a mounted webcam pointed straight down on a desk that can project or stream a top-down video of anything the presenter wants to physically show on their desk. Many teachers use these now instead of the old overhead projectors for showing worksheets, working through math problems, ect while teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife is a Kindergarten teacher and when COVID hit she had to figure out how to teach a bunch of 5 and 6 year olds how to draw letters over Zoom. Initially she made her own document camera using her iPhone and the default camera app. Zoom has a wonderful feature where you can share your iPhone’s screen by plugging into your laptop with a lightning cable or even wirelessly over AirPlay but when you open the camera app there are two issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s a bunch of buttons and chrome around camera view so it looks clunky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The camera app doesn’t actually rotate when you turn it sideways (just some of the labels) so you can only share your phone in portrait mode which means huge black bars on each side of the zoom call and a &lt;em&gt;tiny&lt;/em&gt; video stream of what you want to share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So being the dorky husband that I am, I quickly built an app that does nothing other than show what the phone camera sees with zero chrome, and properly rotates the whole app so that you can share it in landscape on zoom. This did the trick and she actually used it! But over time she’d point out little annoyances and I’d add a feature here and there to make it a smoother experience like a button to turn on the flashlight to light the desk, and one for forcing a rotation change. I also went ahead and fully supported streaming it over AirPlay as a sort of learning experience and before I knew it I had an interesting little app on my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I figured this may be useful for other teachers out there so I gave it a fresh coat of paint, a fun icon (with alternates of course 😄) and put it on the store for free. To be honest, I’m not really sure how many people will find this useful. It’s pretty tailor made for exactly my wife’s use case but I would think that would be a pretty common one for teachers to be in right now in our current virtual teaching world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’ve made it this far, here’s what I’m asking of you. I know most of you probably wouldn’t use this yourselves, but if you know of any teachers or educators in your life that this may help, tell them about the app. It’s totally free for a reason! If getting this into the store makes one teacher’s life easier this year I’ll consider this whole side-project a success 😁.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also made a little video tutorial to show how it works. This video is specifically for use with Zoom, but the same principle should apply to any video conferencing app that lets you share an iPhone screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;postYoutube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fadOMMpQErg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope;  picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;There&apos;s also a link to this video inside of the app as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the app on the App Store &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/id1528900395&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any suggestions for how to improve the app, or if you find an alternate use for it outside of virtual learning, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/overviewer-icon-rounded.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/overviewer-icon-rounded.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">First Sale</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/1/first-sale" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Sale" /><published>2021-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/1/first-sale</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/1/1/first-sale">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; has been in the App Store for over a year, yet I’ve never actually run a sale before. In fact, the only price change I’ve made at all is increasing the price by a few dollars when I shipped my 2.0 update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was due partially to laziness, but also a slight sense of feeling gross about sales for some reason? Truth be told I don’t have a good reason for this, but I had this generic (and quite frankly silly) notion in the back of my mind that it feels slightly desperate and devalues the product somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/frboulais?s=21&quot;&gt;François&lt;/a&gt; reached out about joining his &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/indieappsanta&quot;&gt;Indie App Santa&lt;/a&gt; project and putting Dark Noise on sale for 50% for 1 day I was weirdly hesitant. But I figured “what’s the worst that could happen?” and agreed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on literally no data I kinda figured that I’d probably get around double the sales from the Indie App Santa Twitter account promotion and me tweeting about it from my account. At 50% off this would mean I’d pretty much be breaking even on revenue. Since Dark Noise is paid up front with no subscription or in app purchases, this would basically be a wash with a &lt;em&gt;slight&lt;/em&gt; bump in users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my sales for the month of december. See if you can spot what day the sale took place! 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/01/dark-noise-dec-sales.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise December Sales&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;Note: This is sales, not units so the 50% off is already taken into account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; bigger bump than I was expecting, easily making up for the price difference. It’s worth noting it did trail off pretty quickly after the sale ended. It’s a bit hard to tell exactly how quickly because sales bumped again a few days later on Christmas when the app was mentioned in a few “Best apps for your new phone” articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I’m curious about is what’s driving the sales spike. Indie App Santa has almost 5,000 followers on Twitter who are actively looking for app deals, so I’m curious how much is driven by them and how much is the sale itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets look at the &lt;strong&gt;Sources&lt;/strong&gt; data provided by App Store Connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/01/dark-noise-dec-sources.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Sales Sources&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected Web Referrers and App Store Search have big spikes, but curiously so is App Store Browse (customers who found the app through general App Store browsing vs direct link or specifically searching my app). Possibly this is because the price is lower so more people who saw the app converted to sales? My conversion rate for the day was up 59.3% (though still very low) but there’s so much noise from all the direct sales that this is hard to really tease out what’s really going on here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dig into where the web referrers are coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/01/dark-noise-dec-web-referrers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Web Referrers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;The actual numbers here are much lower than the numbers on the aggregated &quot;Sources&quot; page in App Store Connect. Not sure what to make of that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“t.co” is traffic coming from Twitter (I think that’s something to do with their url shortener or analytics or something?) so that definitely lines up with what I was expecting. And most other referrers are probably from people doing some research on the app through my website or reviews written about it after they saw the app on sale on Twitter. Somebody also made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/AppHookup/comments/khyrg6/iosdark_noise599_299/&quot;&gt;Reddit post&lt;/a&gt; on a subreddit that promotes app sales that drove some sales as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App Referrers also has a few interesting tidbits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/01/01/dark-noise-dec-app-referrers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Web Referrers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;Here again actual numbers are lower than the aggregated &quot;Sources&quot; page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The excellent app &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/dk/app/scriptable/id1405459188&quot;&gt;Scriptable&lt;/a&gt; at the top is, I believe, a result of their &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/scriptableapp/status/1334849125544841216&quot;&gt;partnership with Indie App Santa&lt;/a&gt; where you could make a widget for what app is on sale each day using Scriptable. Tweetbot and Reddit apps make sense for the same reasons as the web traffic (I believe the official Twitter app will always show through Web Referrers because it routes you through Safari when you click links?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting bit here is that there appears to be some apps out there still that track apps with price drops that can drive at least a some sales. I’ll have to experiment at some point by lowering the price with zero promotion and see how that impacts sales for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I think this experience shows me I should definitely be experimenting with pricing and sales more (duh!). I think I still want to keep them relatively infrequent for now, but in 2021 I think I’ll probably do some more experiments to see what I can do when promoting them on my own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dark Noise has been in the App Store for over a year, yet I’ve never actually run a sale before. In fact, the only price change I’ve made at all is increasing the price by a few dollars when I shipped my 2.0 update.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile_1024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile_1024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS 14 Support With Dark Noise 2.1</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2020/9/17/dark-noise-2_1" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS 14 Support With Dark Noise 2.1" /><published>2020-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-09-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2020/9/17/dark-noise-2_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2020/9/17/dark-noise-2_1">&lt;p&gt;With Apple’s release of iOS 14 I’m releasing Dark Noise 2.1 with support for many of the new iOS 14 features. And it’s available in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;App Store today&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;widgets-widgets-widgets&quot;&gt;Widgets Widgets Widgets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020/09/16/dn-big-widgets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Large Widgets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest new feature of Dark Noise 2.1 is multiple new widgets that act as a shortcut to quickly start playing your favorite sounds. There are 3 new widget types to choose from and you can create as many as you want and place them anywhere on your iPhone home screen&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Each of the new widgets allow you to customize the theme and select a noise for each button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020/09/16/dn-single-widgets.png&quot; alt=&quot;Single Widgets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “Single Sound” widget has a few more features. You can configure each one to start your sound with a different timer and even automatically set the volume to your prefered level, perfect for a nighttime routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;other-features&quot;&gt;Other features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the new widgets there are numerous enhancements included in Dark Noise 2.1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020/09/16/dn-timer-popup.png&quot; alt=&quot;New Timer View&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Timer View&lt;/strong&gt; • The timer view has been rewritten to make setting a timer more streamlined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020/09/16/dn-siri-more.png&quot; alt=&quot;Siri Enhancements&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Siri Support&lt;/strong&gt; • When asking Siri to play a sound on Dark Noise that has multiple options, Siri will show you the alternatives and you can select a different sound to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2020/09/16/dn-icon-picker.png&quot; alt=&quot;New Icon Picker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New App Icon Selection Page&lt;/strong&gt; • The app icon selection page has been rebuilt to show off the alternate app icons a little bit better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wind Down&lt;/strong&gt; • Dark Noise will now show up in the new iOS Wind Down feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 2.1 is available on for iPhone and iPad on the App Store &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;promo-video&quot;&gt;Promo Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;postYoutube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YEXRx5wZ-cw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope;  picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For context read &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1306004068201123841?s=21&quot;&gt;this Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; on the long windy road to getting this through to the store&lt;/em&gt; 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;On the iPad they are currently still limited to the “Today View” to the left of your home screens.. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With Apple’s release of iOS 14 I’m releasing Dark Noise 2.1 with support for many of the new iOS 14 features. And it’s available in the App Store today!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>