<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-26T08:33:33-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Charlie Chapman</title><subtitle>The personal blog of Charlie Chapman.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Never mind</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2024/8/2/nevermind" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Never mind" /><published>2024-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-08-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2024/8/2/nevermind</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2024/8/2/nevermind">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2024/08/nevermind-blog-header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this is embarrassing. I &lt;a href=&quot;./2024-07-19-summer-of-the-blog.md&quot;&gt;set out a goal&lt;/a&gt; to write a blog post per week this summer and I didn’t even make it to week two!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a boat load of excuses but ultimately, I just unexpectedly don’t have the capacity right now. I still have some stuff I’m working on, and of course trying to get &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; ready for iOS 18 in September. But yeah… guess I’m just gonna have to take the L on this one.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/posts/2024/08/nevermind-blog-header.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/posts/2024/08/nevermind-blog-header.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer of the Blog</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2024/7/19/summer-of-the-blog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer of the Blog" /><published>2024-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-07-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2024/7/19/summer-of-the-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2024/7/19/summer-of-the-blog">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2024/07/summer-of-the-blog-header.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR:&lt;/strong&gt; I want to post to my blog at least once a week for the rest of the summer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE&quot;&gt;CGP Grey’s theme concept&lt;/a&gt; over traditional New Year’s resolutions with more concrete goals. But every once in a while, specific goals have been really effective for me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heck, my whole career effectively changed because of a set of New Year’s goals I made in 2019. To refresh my After Effects skills after a long break from having kids, I set out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/_chuckyc/status/1080137244722282499&quot;&gt;make a short animation once a week&lt;/a&gt;. I also set a goal release an &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/_chuckyc/status/1130646235990429696&quot;&gt;iOS app to the App Store&lt;/a&gt; by the end of that year to bootstrap my Swift knowledge after joining an iOS team at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both goals eventually converged into my animation heavy app &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ve been a side-hustling indie developer ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;I&amp;#39;m going to try something new this year. After a couple years of neglect, I&amp;#39;m going to try to kick start my &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/mograph?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#mograph&lt;/a&gt; skills with a weekly animation project I&amp;#39;m calling &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/WeeklyMograph?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;#WeeklyMograph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My goal is to create one animation every week in 2019. Doesn&amp;#39;t have to be great, just finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uU54mj7gCm&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uU54mj7gCm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Charlie Chapman (@_chuckyc) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1080137244722282499?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;January 1, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find goals that require a regular cadence of output to be really effective for me. The deadline, even self-imposed, of a once a week animation really forced me into a habit of regularly doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last 4 years I’ve been running my podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com/&quot;&gt;Launched&lt;/a&gt; with a self-imposed deadline of delivering an episode every 2 weeks. This really forced me to push off my natural (incredibly strong) procrastination and get things done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/_chuckyc/status/1740802949260197998&quot;&gt;announcing the semi-hiatus of Launched&lt;/a&gt; this year, I haven’t had that kind of regular motivation to keep pushing myself on growing outside of my normal job. And honestly, I really miss it. I notice myself getting slower and struggling more to be productive even in the day job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I want some kind of lightweight recurring goal to kickstart my creative output again. I’m not ready to commit to the grind of a regular podcast schedule (yet 😏) but there &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a particular skill I’ve been wanting to grow lately: &lt;strong&gt;writing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing is a pretty important part of my &lt;a href=&quot;https://x.com/_chuckyc/status/1655594409818312705&quot;&gt;job as a Developer Advocate&lt;/a&gt;, but I’ve found I really struggle with it. Particularly with speed. I write painfully slowly. I have enough taste to recognize that what I’m writing is bad, but not enough skill to get it to the point of sounding good. So I just get hung up writing and rewriting sentences trying to get it sounding right before eventually getting distracted with some other task I know I can do. And before I know it, hours have gone by and I’ve barely eked out a few paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-summer-of-the-blog&quot;&gt;The Summer of the Blog&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’m going to make the rest of this season my &lt;strong&gt;Summer of the Blog&lt;/strong&gt;. My goal is to post something, anything, to my blog at least once a week. It doesn’t have to be good, it just has to be shipped. And it can even simply be linking out to something else I’ve made like a podcast episode or a video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m setting the bar pretty low here because I want it to be easily achievable. The real goal is to get into the habit of regularly publishing, and force myself to put words down with a hard deadline that they have to go out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m calling it the Summer of the Blog because I want to publicly commit to maintaining this through the end of the summer, which Google tells me ends September 22nd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this all bets are off because my children’s school starts back up and my fall conference travel season kicks back off. I’d love to keep the pace up after that though, but I’ll have achieved my goal if I make it that far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will I write about? I don’t know yet! I have a lot of blog posts rolling around in my head that I’ve never taken the time to write. The goal here is building up my writing muscles to get over writers block more than building up some kind of audience, so ultimately I’ll write about whatever I’m passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s absolutely killing me how long this post already is and I want to spend the next few hours trimming it down and hopelessly flaily to get it sounding better. But I’m not.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/posts/2024/07/summer-of-the-blog-header.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/posts/2024/07/summer-of-the-blog-header.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Vision Pro</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/12/7/on-vision-pro" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Vision Pro" /><published>2023-12-07T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-12-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/12/7/on-vision-pro</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/12/7/on-vision-pro">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This post was hastily written on my iPhone while traveling so please forgive the typos.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I write this, I’m sitting at an airport, on my way to New York to attend a developer lab with Apple to try out Dark Noise on Vision Pro. This time tomorrow I don’t think I’ll be able to really share my thoughts on the product until after its release “early next year”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And boy… do I have thoughts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I want to write them all down. Not as some smart tech insider who understands the ecosystem and can predict how this new product category will succeed or fail in the market. But more as a time capsule to capture the thoughts of a random iOS developer at this point in time. This will probably be an overly long and unorganized rambling… so you’ve been warned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cut to the chase… I don’t understand this product. Not just this expensive V1 pseudo-devkit they’re releasing next year. But also the whole future version of this overall product category, even after a bunch of incremental improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I explain myself, I want to be clear. I am extremely excited about it all. It looks incredible from a technical and design perspective. It genuinely feels deeply thought through from the privacy angle, overal experience, and of course the classic Apple fit and finish. From what’s been shared publicly so far, everyone who’s worked on it should be extremely proud. Heck, I’m flying to New York just to spend a day trying it out and trying to understand how my app fits on this new platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But I don’t understand it as a mass market product.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with what &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; makes sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;home-theater&quot;&gt;Home Theater&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vision Pro looks incredible for watching movies. As long as you’re doing it alone anyway. No doubt it’s going to be hard to beat immersing yourself in a beautiful environment, looking at an enormous screen, and listening to wonderful simulated Dolby Atmos surround sound while sitting on your couch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even someone like me, who’s rarely watching a movie completely alone, will enjoy this for the occasional show I watch on my own on my iPad while my wife sits next to me in the living room watching something else. The pass through feature means I won’t feel totally isolated since I can still easily see her and can presumably pause and easily talk to her at any point (as long as the weird outward facing eyes on the headset don’t freak her out too much 😅).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if the experience is actually good while on a plane? That would be amazing! Assuming it’s culturally acceptable and I wouldn’t feel like a total weirdo putting a big screen on my face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a $3,500 super nice personal home theater isn’t a mass market product. And that brings us to gaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting here in 2023, gaming is the obvious area of focus for a VR headset. So far, it’s the only place where VR has really found any product market fit, with Meta and Valve leading the charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple doesn’t seem to be addressing this market… at all? The gaming segment of the Vision Pro announcement video simply showed that you could pair a normal Playstation controller and play flat 2D Apple Arcade games on a big screen floating in front of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feels completely bizarre to me. The iPhone has been a massive success in gaming, so I figured they would, at the very least, support some kind of 3rd Party VR hand controllers and allow VR games made for the Quest and Vive to be ported over to Vision Pro? It seems like it’d be the best non-tethered VR gaming system by a decent margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to be fair, VR gaming hasn’t exactly been a game-changing platform. People buy them, and enjoy them. But they’re tiny platforms compared to traditional TV consoles like the Playstation, Xbox, and Switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meetings&quot;&gt;Meetings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A frequently cited use case for VR as a platform is better meetings. A lot of digital ink has been spilled about how much more “presence” or “immersion” VR can provide when on a virtual meeting compared to a traditional conference call platform like Zoom or FaceTime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has never really made any sense to me. Maybe I’m being a luddite here, but even the most advanced version of a future VR based meeting experience I can imagine will still be worse than a mediocre web cam based video call. There’s sooooo much information being conveyed by simply seeing an actual representation of a person at that point in time (in the context of their space at that point in time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ooh did you get a haircut, looks great!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You look really tired, you doing ok?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Whoa it’s dark there, is it storming there?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of interactions happen constantly for me and help build a relationship and further trust with my team/family/friends. Losing that information resolution would require some kind of major gain from the technology. And a “feeling of presence” is difficult for me to imagine overcoming those drawbacks. But I’ve also never tired it myself, so maybe I’ll be surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do think there is a story around the “presence” thing where VR could enable a group meeting experience where multiple people could be in the same room and sustain multiple, separate concurrent conversations, which traditional video conferencing doesn’t really allow for currently. But that’s definitely not what I’ve seen from anybody so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;productivity&quot;&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the one area where I can see a sliver of a compelling story for the future of VisionOS as a larger platform than just a personal home theater.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can imagine a world where I sit at my home office, usually alone, and instead of staring at a desk full of monitors, I put on a headset and have an infinite canvas of big windows and maybe even some 3d elements all around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an experience the V1 Vision Pro can somewhat provide. Though the limited power means it couldn’t replace my Mac, and the current iteration of Mac mirroring limits you to a single 4K window. But I can project out a future of incremental improvements that get there. Maybe I could plug my battery pack directly into a beefier Mac for all of my heavier loads like Video Editing. And I’d probably still use a keyboard and trackpad. But that sounds like a nice experience and a much less cluttered desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, importantly, this still wouldn’t replace my laptop. I’m not going to use this when my wife and I are planning a vacation, where we both are constantly showing each other our screens. Or take it to a coffee shop. Or take meeting notes in a customer meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But as a solo use only desktop enhancement (or even replacement if your workload isn’t super heavy), yeah sure this would be a great experience. But how big is that market? And the price would have to drop way lower if that’s the only story right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-ar-glasses&quot;&gt;Full AR Glasses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“But wait!”&lt;/em&gt; I hear you say. &lt;em&gt;“This isn’t about a VR headset, this is just the stepping stone to the eventual AR Glasses!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a framing of this product that’s been around forever, but I don’t think that product is even on a 10 year time horizon from now. I’m not even sure we’ll ever see that product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I’m aware, there doesn’t exist a display technology that’s transparent, with the the ability to fully obscure your view (to render blacks), contains a backlight (to render whites), and can move the focus distance feet away from your eyes. I can imagine a version of this current product that’s been miniaturized down enough to look like some old-time motorcycle goggles or something, but I find it difficult to believe AR glasses, the way many people have described them, are remotely in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So what now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know! Maybe this is exactly how people have felt about other revolutionary devices. I think, at the very least, Apple and others pursuing VR/AR are at least inventing a lot of cool technology that will make sense in other types of products with clear product market fit. It sure feels like the Spatial Audio features of AirPods may have come out of some of the work for VisionOS. Maybe it’ll be like Google Wave. A product not long for this world, but some innovations that live on to power other products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way I’m truly excited to see how it all plays out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Note: This post was hastily written on my iPhone while traveling so please forgive the typos.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile-2023.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile-2023.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise Interactive Widgets &amp;amp; iOS 17 Support</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/9/18/dark-noise-3_2-iOS-17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise Interactive Widgets &amp;amp; iOS 17 Support" /><published>2023-09-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/9/18/dark-noise-3_2-iOS-17</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/9/18/dark-noise-3_2-iOS-17">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/09/18/dark-noise-3_2-interactive-widgets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Interactive Widgets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I’ve released &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; 3.2 with support for iOS 17 and the all new interactive widgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise widgets have been rebuilt from the ground up to support the all new interactive widgets in iOS 17. This means you can start and stop a sound right from your widget without needing to open the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/09/18/dark-noise-3_2-widget-screenshots.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Interactive Widgets Screenshots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are now 8 different widget’s to choose from, each with 12 themes you can configure between. The small widgets all work wonderfully with iOS 17’s new StandBy mode, making it easier than ever to start your favorite ambient noise when you go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;postYoutube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/riiWuoLxj1c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope;  picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 3.2 is available on the App Store to &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;try for free&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/posts/2023/09/18/dark-noise-3_2-interactive-widgets.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/posts/2023/09/18/dark-noise-3_2-interactive-widgets.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Launched Diary: Dark Noise 3.0</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/12/launched-diary-dark-noise-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Launched Diary: Dark Noise 3.0" /><published>2023-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/12/launched-diary-dark-noise-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/12/launched-diary-dark-noise-3">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by David Smith’s wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/radar/110&quot;&gt;Launch Diary episode of Under the Radar&lt;/a&gt; I tried something a little fun last week and recorded an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/posts/launched-diary-3-81409064&quot;&gt;audio diary&lt;/a&gt; of my experience launching the big &lt;a href=&quot;https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3&quot;&gt;Dark Noise 3.0 update&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My original thought was that it would be a member-only episode for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/launched&quot;&gt;Launched Patreon&lt;/a&gt;, but after listening I decided I wanted it to be a little more accessible than that. The episode is available to listen to for free and Launched members will see it automatically appear in their podcast player if they’re subscribed to their member Launched Pro feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you find this helpful, or at least interesting! If folks like this type of thing I’d like to do more things like this for patrons in the future. If you have any ideas I’d love to hear them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can listen to the episode (and become a member if you want to support the show 😉) on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/posts/launched-diary-3-81409064&quot;&gt;Launched Patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Inspired by David Smith’s wonderful Launch Diary episode of Under the Radar I tried something a little fun last week and recorded an audio diary of my experience launching the big Dark Noise 3.0 update.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/launched_artwork-1024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/launched_artwork-1024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise 3.0: White noise, freed</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise 3.0: White noise, freed" /><published>2023-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-04-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/4/2/dark-noise-3">&lt;p&gt;Today &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;Dark Noise 3.0&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; released on the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest change in Dark Noise 3.0 is the introduction of a new free tier. This free tier includes access to 8 free sounds, as well as full support for infinitely looping sounds, Shortcuts, Siri integration, the Timer, and all the deep Apple integrations you’ve come to expect from Dark Noise. This makes the app more accessible than it’s ever been before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who want more features and sounds, there is &lt;strong&gt;Dark Noise Pro&lt;/strong&gt;. This optional subscription or lifetime in-app purchase unlocks over 50 sounds, the ability to create custom mixes, alternate app icons, and alternate premium themes. With Dark Noise Pro, you can customize your white noise experience to your liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/04/02/dark-noise-pro-compare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Tier Comparisons&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on this update for quite a while, and a significant portion of that time was spent ensuring existing customers are taken care of. Customers who purchased Dark Noise before this update are called &lt;strong&gt;Dark Originals&lt;/strong&gt;. At launch, they will have all Dark Noise Pro features unlocked automatically. There &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be features introduced in the future that require a Dark Noise Pro subscription, but for now Dark Originals will receive all of the same features as Dark Noise Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 3.0 also begins the process of improving the experience of Dark Noise with headphones or nicer speakers. This update includes &lt;strong&gt;4 high quality stereo remasters&lt;/strong&gt; of existing sounds: Rain, Thunderstorm, Beach, and Airplane Interior. Future updates will include more remasters as well as a new focus on increasing the variety of sounds in Dark Noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, this update includes a plethora of small enhancements and bug fixes including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Newly updated App Icon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rewritten theme picker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Aurora premium theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Aurora alternate app icon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mac window size restores from previous session&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 3.0 is available &lt;strong&gt;now&lt;/strong&gt; on the App Store to &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;download for free&lt;/a&gt;! I can’t wait to hear what you all think. If you’re press you can find an extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/press&quot;&gt;press-kit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/posts/dark-noise-3&quot;&gt;more details&lt;/a&gt; on the release on &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;darknoise.app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Today Dark Noise 3.0 is finally released on the App Store.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-icon-v2-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-icon-v2-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise Analytics: March 2023</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/3/1/2023-dark-noise-stats" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise Analytics: March 2023" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/3/1/2023-dark-noise-stats</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2023/3/1/2023-dark-noise-stats">&lt;p&gt;I recently added some analytics into &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; using the new(ish) privacy-focused analytics tool &lt;a href=&quot;https://telemetrydeck.com/&quot;&gt;TelemetryDeck&lt;/a&gt; in preparation for my big update that will be adding a free tier. I want to get an understanding of how many users I might be dealing with going forward and some of my future plans lead me to want to understand what features, and sounds users are using most within the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been a couple of months now so I have enough data to share some metrics with you all. I think it might be fun to see what changes when I switch to a subscription business model with a free tier. As always, this is meant to be helpful! I don’t know if these numbers are higher than average, or lower than average. This is just one data point that’s hopefully helpful to see, especially for other indie developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, let’s start with the high-level stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-overview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s only been a couple of months, but so far &lt;strong&gt;Monthly Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; have hovered right around &lt;strong&gt;11,000 to 12,000&lt;/strong&gt; unique users. For reference, App Store Connect’s “Active Last 30 Days” analytics (which are limited to only users who opt-in) shows 4,300 users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Daily Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; is surprisingly consistent at around &lt;strong&gt;2,300 to 2,500&lt;/strong&gt; unique users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-hourly-active.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Hourly Active Users&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Hourly Active Users&lt;/strong&gt; very clearly show peaks around nighttime in North America with a smaller peak in the morning confirming my assumption that a large portion of users are probably playing these sounds to go to sleep. The smaller peak in the morning is most likely because most people pause the app in the background or use the timer feature to automatically stop the sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;device-info&quot;&gt;Device Info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-device-info.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Device Info&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at device info, about &lt;strong&gt;1/5th&lt;/strong&gt; of sessions came from &lt;strong&gt;Macs vs iOS&lt;/strong&gt; which I have to admit surprised me to be that high. Good to keep in mind that the Mac does represent a significant portion of my app’s use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over &lt;strong&gt;90%&lt;/strong&gt; of sessions came from the &lt;strong&gt;latest iOS 16 or macOS 13&lt;/strong&gt;. This will be interesting to watch as I add a free tier. I think there’s a chance that a more accessible app will get a higher adoption among the less tech-enthusiast crowd which may actually increase the percentage of users I have on older OSs. Also, hello there iOS 17! 👋&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;noise-play-counts&quot;&gt;Noise Play Counts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-noise-bar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Device Info&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-noise-donut.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Noise Count Donut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wow… Brown Noise is king apparently 😅.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expected some popular sounds and then a long tail, but I definitely didn’t expect Brown Noise to be that dominant. It’s cool to see custom mixes are very popular though. I get a lot of positive feedback about that feature, but I always wondered how popular it was to use by most people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;extras&quot;&gt;Extras&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2023/03/01/dark-noise-stats-2023-extras.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise 2023 Stats Extras&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a couple of extra metrics I found interesting. There’s not a lot to analyze here other than it’s nice to have confirmation people really are using these features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wrap-up&quot;&gt;Wrap Up&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m definitely glad I finally added some light analytics back in the app. I think this will be really helpful in guiding decisions on what features or sounds I should focus on going forward. And while TelemetryDeck is still a little young and rough around the edges, I feel confident in that team’s focus on privacy. And even in the short few months I’ve been using it they’ve dramatically improved the reporting UI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this is helpful for you all! At the very least I think it’ll be an interesting data point to look back on in a few months after my update to subscriptions and having a free tier. As always, if you have any questions or comments I’d love to hear them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@charliemchapman&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I recently added some analytics into Dark Noise using the new(ish) privacy-focused analytics tool TelemetryDeck in preparation for my big update that will be adding a free tier. I want to get an understanding of how many users I might be dealing with going forward and some of my future plans lead me to want to understand what features, and sounds users are using most within the app.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2022: A Break, a Breakthrough, and a Breakdown?</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2022/12/31/2022-break-breakthrough-breakdown" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022: A Break, a Breakthrough, and a Breakdown?" /><published>2022-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2022/12/31/2022-break-breakthrough-breakdown</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2022/12/31/2022-break-breakthrough-breakdown">&lt;p&gt;2022 was a bit of a weird year for me that I think kinda breaks down into 3 distinct parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A break&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A breakthrough&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And… a breakdown?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-break&quot;&gt;A Break&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since switching to iOS development and launching &lt;a href=&quot;https://darknoise.app/&quot;&gt;Dark Noise&lt;/a&gt; in 2019, I’ve been working pretty consistently hard on side project work. I wanted to establish myself in this platform and this community so I could avoid getting pulled back into web development like previously always ended up happening. Dark Noise and my podcast &lt;a href=&quot;https://launchedfm.com/&quot;&gt;Launched&lt;/a&gt; were both mechanisms to keep pushing on both the technical/product side and the community side of things. This was especially important when the pandemic showed up and made connecting with the community much more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But 2022 was different. I was finally able to travel. We had just bought a new house at the end of 2021. And &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; I was a little burnt out? I’m not quite sure the full alchemy of reasons, but from the beginning of the year to the end of the summer my side projects really took a back seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did keep producing Launched thanks to a schedule that pulled me along and a lineup of guests I was, quite frankly, extremely proud to have on. But Dark Noise development slowed to a crawl. I spun up a couple &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1504267868241862656&quot;&gt;new app ideas&lt;/a&gt; that I ran out of steam on and never released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it had an impact! Dark Noise sales were down pretty significantly the first half of the year. I had no major releases in that period and being a paid up front app meant that really hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2022/12/31/dark-noise-yearly-proceeds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise yearly sales graph&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;Dark Noise yearly proceeds (released in August 2019)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might all sound negative but I took advantage of this break and honestly I think I needed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got to travel! I finally met coworkers for the first time in San Diego, vacationed with my wife without kids for the first time since the pandemic, went to Europe for the very first time (with the kids!), and &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got to meet folks in the iOS community &lt;strong&gt;in person&lt;/strong&gt; at WWDC 😱.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2022/12/31/2022-flighty-passport.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Flighty Passport showing all flights I took in 2022&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;postCaption&quot;&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://flighty.app/&quot;&gt;Flighty&lt;/a&gt; Passport showing all of my 2022 flights&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also in between traveling, Apple reached out asking for a demo version of the Dark Noise Mac app. And now &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1585347257737818113&quot;&gt;every Apple retail store in the world has a demo of Dark Noise pre-installed on all of their display Macs&lt;/a&gt;! 😱&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-breakthrough&quot;&gt;A Breakthrough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things happened at the end of summer that changed my side project trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dark-noise-returns&quot;&gt;Dark Noise Returns&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is simply Apple’s OS release cadence. The nice thing about Apple’s release cadence is it sort of forces me to get a release pulled together by a certain date. This year, that meant I needed Dark Noise to be ready with iOS 16 support and features like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DarkNoiseApp/status/1569328284923486211&quot;&gt;new Lock Screen widgets&lt;/a&gt; in September with a follow up release in October to support the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DarkNoiseApp/status/1584549536269148162&quot;&gt;new Dynamic Island and Live Activities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release kind of woke me up from the side project blues and got the gears going again with regards to Dark Noise development. This was partially fueled by extra time I now had because of the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; breakthrough I had at the end of summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;launched-with-help&quot;&gt;Launched With Help&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August I decided I needed some help with Launched. Editing the show was simply taking too much of my limited side project time. I wanted to hire an editor, which meant I needed money. I didn’t want to take on selling sponsorships myself given I was already stretched too thin so I started putting together a pitch deck to see if I could find a network that would let Launched join.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking over the pitch deck stats I basically chickened out thinking the numbers were probably too low for anyone to consider and never even reached out to anyone. Instead I simply &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_chuckyc/status/1561695800656379904&quot;&gt;tweeted them out&lt;/a&gt; and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, this ended up paying off! &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@refactoredd@mastodon.online&quot;&gt;Jonathan Ruiz&lt;/a&gt; had recently ended his show, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/_everydayrobots&quot;&gt;Everyday Robots&lt;/a&gt;, and reached out to offer to edit the Launched. I took him up on the offer and every episode since has been edited by Jonathan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cannot express how big of an impact this has had. I am pretty precious with the edit of that show, but Jonathan has been outstanding. And the time it’s freed up has allowed me to pour more time into growing both the podcast (I’m gearing up to start taking on sponsorships) &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; turning Dark Noise into a potentially fully viable business into it’s own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-breakdown&quot;&gt;A Breakdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: ok this headline is a pretty hyperbolic for the sake of keeping the “break” theme but you have to admit it’s pretty catchy yeah?&lt;/em&gt; 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of 2022 has been… turbulent to say the least. The tech industry has suddenly gotten a little unstable. And Twitter, the platform that the hosts the community I’d invested so much in, was imploding. There are also some personal career things I can’t discuss here that put me, an extremely risk averse personality, into hardcore de-risking mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started putting together action plans. What do I do if I get laid off? How much runway do I have to find another job? Can I grow that runway if my side projects are making more money? Could my side projects &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; the other job?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brewed a pretty weird concoction of excitement mixed with anxiety that’s launching me into 2023 with a pretty clearly defined set of short term goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Switch Dark Noise to a subscription model.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Monetize Launched with a combination of sponsorships and membership/Patreon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Invest in the local (St. Louis) iOS community by starting some kind of meetup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like my goals have usually been more high-minded and &lt;em&gt;“personal growth”&lt;/em&gt; focused in years past. It feels a little crass for a major theme to essentially be &lt;em&gt;“make more money”&lt;/em&gt; but this is where I am. We’ll see where 2023 takes me, but either way I’m at least coming into it with a side-eye towards handling uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">2022 was a bit of a weird year for me that I think kinda breaks down into 3 distinct parts. A break A breakthrough And… a breakdown?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile_1024.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/charlie-profile_1024.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">iOS 15 Support with Dark Noise 2.6</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/10/5/dark-noise-2_6-iOS-15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS 15 Support with Dark Noise 2.6" /><published>2021-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/10/5/dark-noise-2_6-iOS-15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/10/5/dark-noise-2_6-iOS-15">&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise 2.6 comes to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;App Store today&lt;/a&gt; with full support for iOS 15!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;extra-large-widgets&quot;&gt;Extra Large Widgets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/10/05/dark-noise-2_6-extra-large-widgets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Extra Large Widgets&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS 15 introduced a new widget size exclusive to iPad and Dark Noise 2.6 adds support for these new big sizes. Now you can fill your iPad with 16 wide button noises, or a whopping 32 square button noises in a single widget!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course these widgets support all of the themes and customizations you’ve come to expect from Dark Noise widgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shortcuts&quot;&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/10/05/dark-noise-2_6-shortcuts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Shortcuts Actions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to limitations in iOS 14, Shortcuts actions with parameters could not play audio without opening the app up in the foreground. This led to a confusing array of Shortcuts actions provided by Dark Noise. Shortcuts actions &lt;strong&gt;with parameters&lt;/strong&gt; for setting up a timer or volume (began with the word “Start”) had to open the app in the foreground to start a sound, and shortcuts with &lt;strong&gt;no parameters&lt;/strong&gt; (began with the word “Play”) were limited but could play sounds in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With iOS 15 things are dramatically simpler. New “Play [Noise]” Shortcuts actions can play noises in the background &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; have parameter options for customizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also a new Shortcut action called “Find [Noise]” for advanced Shortcuts users. This action accepts a string parameter, searches Dark Noise for a matching noise, and outputs a Noise object that the new “Play [Noise]” action will accept as an input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows for more advanced automations where you want to dynamically pass in a string for which noise you would like to play.  To be honest I’m not entirely sure what the main use case for this is, but I’ve recieved enough requests for it that I thought it was worth adding. I’d love to hear from anybody who uses it to see what they’ve built!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes-and-improvements&quot;&gt;Bug Fixes and Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new timer view using iOS 15’s new half sheet popover and some minor bug fixes round out the update. This year’s iOS beta cycle has been… busy to say the least (I moved into a new house!). Things are finally settling down and I’m getting back to work on Dark Noises next major feature!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dark Noise 2.6 comes to the App Store today with full support for iOS 15!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-app-icon-cropped.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Dark Noise for Mac</title><link href="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/5/25/dark-noise-mac" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dark Noise for Mac" /><published>2021-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/5/25/dark-noise-mac</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://charliemchapman.com/posts/2021/5/25/dark-noise-mac">&lt;div class=&quot;postYoutube&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wsMA6Du03J8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope;  picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise has come to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;Mac App Store&lt;/a&gt;! The sleek UI and large selection of ambient sounds you know and love are now easier than ever to use while you work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mini-player&quot;&gt;Mini Player&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/05/25/dark-noise-mac-mini-player.png&quot; alt=&quot;Big Sounds Mini Player&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking advantage of the Mac platform, a new innovative “adaptive toolbar” UI allows you to shrink your window into a Mini Player to keep Dark Noise quickly accessible while taking up very little screen space. Dark Noise for Mac also features full menu support with keyboard shortcuts to feel right at home on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-your-favorite-features&quot;&gt;All your favorite features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/05/25/dark-noise-mac-themes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Themes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of your favorite Dark Noise features are here including timers, custom mixes, widgets, and multiple themes. And with iCloud syncing, all of your custom mixes will automatically be available on your Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-it-now&quot;&gt;Get it now!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/posts/2021/05/25/dark-noise-hero-2_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dark Noise Family&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark Noise for Mac is now available on the App Store &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/dark-noise/id1465439395&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as a universal app including the iPhone and iPad versions. Existing Dark Noise customers will be able to download Dark Noise for Mac for free.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-mac-rounded_1024.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://charliemchapman.com/assets/images/dark-noise-mac-rounded_1024.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>